zoomrewards.com 2012-12-13

# ZoomPanel - Privacy Policy

## Zoomerang, ZoomPanel and TrueSample Privacy Policy

Updated June 20, 2012.

This privacy policy explains how SurveyMonkey collects, uses, transfers or otherwise handles personally identifiable information from you, a visitor to the Zoomerang, ZoomPanel and TrueSample websites operated by SurveyMonkey (collectively, the “ **Site** ”). 

### Scope

This privacy policy only covers data collected through the Site. This privacy policy does not cover any other data collection or processing practices, including, without limitation, the practices of other web pages to which we link or of users of our services provided through the Site (e.g., users of our Zoomerang service). When we refer to this privacy policy in notices and consent requests related to surveys, special-purpose web pages or otherwise, this privacy policy applies as modified in the particular notice or consent request (e.g., with respect to types of data collected or purposes of collection). 

SurveyMonkey.com, LLC has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe's program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy_seals_and_services/consumer_privacy/privacy-programs-requirements.html) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. The TRUSTe program covers information collected through this website, [zoomerang.com](http://www.zoomerang.com/), [zoompanel.com](http://www.zoompanel.com/) and [truesample.com](http://www.truesample.com/). TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us using the details in the “Contact Us” section below. If you are not satisfied with our response you can [contact TRUSTe](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint). 

SurveyMonkey.com, LLC complies with the [US-EU and US-Swiss Safe Harbor Frameworks](http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/) as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use and retention of personal information from European Union member countries and Switzerland. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view SurveyMonkey.com, LLC’s certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>. 

### Types of Data and Collection Methods

Through the Site, we collect data that you actively submit (“ **Actively Submitted Data** ”) as well as data that we collect about you from other sources (“ **Passively Tracked Data** ”): 

_Actively Submitted Data_ : When you request information, subscribe to a mailing list or for a service, register as a user, post to one of our forums or communities, send or respond to an online survey or otherwise actively send us data, we usually collect data such as your name, email address(es), telephone number(s), country of residency, and certain information related to the business you represent (if any). In connection with chargeable services, we will also collect payment information (e.g., credit card number and related verification information). In connection with our own surveys, directed at ZoomPanel members, we ask questions related to the topic of the survey. When you use our tools to send out your own surveys, you decide who to contact and what questions to ask. In each such instance, however, you will know what data we collect through the Site, because you have asked your survey respondents to actively submit it. 

_Passively Tracked Data_ : When you visit the Site, we also passively track information on your computer and Internet connection, such as the IP address of your computer and/or Internet service provider, the date and time you access the Site, the Internet address of web sites from which you link to or arrive at the Site, the computer technology you are using and your movements and preferences on our Site. We use technology that many other web sites employ, including, without limitation, "cookies" or small data files stored on your computer's hard drive, to collect information such as the aforementioned. In some instances, we also use cookies to collect information in connection with future visits from that web site, to recognize you as a previous visitor and to track your activity at our Site. You do not need to have cookies turned on to participate in our surveys or to visit our Site. You can refuse cookies by turning them off on your browser, but please note that this may adversely affect your user experience and convenience. 

_Combinations_ : Unless you also actively submit personal information such as your name or address in connection with Passively Tracked Data, Passively Tracked Data does not typically allow us to identify you personally. (Even though it theoretically could be done, we do not try to find out who you are, unless we need to comply with a legal obligation.) To the extent permitted by applicable law, we reserve the right to combine Passively Tracked Data or data available via a third party with personal data that you choose to actively submit. We do this for some survey "panels" (which may be deployed on Zoomerang.com or other sites). Specifically if you take surveys from us we will "fingerprint" your system in order to combat fraud. In generating this "fingerprint" we gather only publically available information from your browser; this includes your IP address, browser version, and other similar types of information. 

### Collection Purposes, Use of Data

_Passively Tracked Data_ : We collect Passively Tracked Data primarily for purposes of administering, protecting and improving our Site and our systems, to better understand the preferences of our Site visitors, to compile aggregated statistics about Site usage, and to help personalize your experience on our Site. We also use cookies and Passively Tracked Data to protect the integrity of surveys, e.g., to prevent survey respondents from responding to the same survey twice. 

For some survey panels we will verify the information that you, or a third party, provide us and/or combine the information you provide with information we may gather from additional sources. Verification of personal data may be done on our systems, or done by a third party. If your personal data is provided to us for verification purposes only we will never store any of your personal information on our systems (we store only the results of the verification process). 

_Actively Submitted Data_ : We collect Actively Submitted Data primarily for two purposes: Firstly, for the purpose for which you originally sent us the data e.g., to receive the service you requested, to confirm your registration for a service, to run a survey, to allow you to run a survey, to bill you for services or to send you information or materials that you requested. Secondly, for the purposes of informing you about our products and services; additionally, you can opt out of receiving marketing emails as explained below. 

### Cookies

We use cookies on our websites. Cookies are small bits of data we store on the device you use to access our services so we can recognize repeat users. Each cookie expires after a certain period of time, depending on what we use it for. We use cookies for several reasons: 

  * _For security reasons_. We use cookies to authenticate your identity, such as confirming whether you are currently logged into our website.
  * _To provide you with personalized content_. We may store user preferences, such as your default language, in cookies to personalize the content you see.
  * _To improve our services_. We use cookies to measure your usage of our websites and track referral data, as well as to occasionally display different versions of content to you. This information helps us to develop and improve our services and optimize the content we display to users./li>

The use of cookies by our third party service providers is not covered by our privacy policy. We do not have access or control over these cookies (other than allowing the third parties to set these cookies via our websites). For example, we use Google Analytics, which helps us to analyze usage of our websites. Google Analytics sets cookies to assist it to identify users and analyze their usage on an anonymous and/or aggregated basis. 

### Web Beacons

Our web pages may contain electronic images known as web beacons (sometimes called single-pixel gifs) and are used along with cookies to compile aggregated statistics to analyze how our site is used, and also to measure the effectiveness of our online marketing and advertising campaigns. Web beacons may be used in some of our emails to let us know which emails and links have been opened by recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of our customer communications and marketing campaigns. 

### Disclosures of Personal Information

We are not in the business of selling or renting your information to telemarketers and do not share your personally identifiable information with others, except as follows: 

  * We may share your information with affiliated companies for reward redemption and/or other market research opportunities.
  * If you use any of our services with a corporate email account (i.e., an account for employees, contractors, etc. as opposed to a personal email account with a general email service provider such as AOL, Hotmail, Yahoo, Gmail, etc.), and such corporation signs up for an enterprise account with us or is considering an enterprise account, we may inform such corporation of your use of our service, so that you can benefit from enterprise pricing and any other benefits negotiated by the corporation for its registered users or otherwise arising from such coordination.
  * We also engage agents and service providers who have access to data, but only to process such data on our behalf and for our purposes under confidentiality agreements.
  * We may share your information as required by law or in the interest of protecting or exercising our or others' legal rights, e.g., without limitation, in connection with requests from law enforcement officials and in connection with court proceedings.
  * We may share or transfer your information in connection with a prospective or actual sale, merger, transfer or other reorganization of all or parts of our business.
  * We reserve the right to use and disclose any information collected via the Site that is not in personally identifiable form.
  * We do not share, sell, rent or trade your personally identifiable information with third parties for their promotional purposes.

Without limiting the generality of the foregoing, note that we will NOT share your identity or your individual responses to surveys that we conduct ourselves with customers who may have commissioned such surveys; we only provide aggregate response data to survey customers. But, as noted in the next section, we do not control how others may use our tools when they conduct surveys through our website. 

### Third Party Data Collection Through Our Site

When one of our users deploys our tools to send out survey response requests or otherwise to collect data, e.g., through zoomerang.com, such user will receive and process any responses. We will host, but not access such information, except in connection with technical support, with the consent of the user who conducted the survey, or in any other manner permitted by this privacy policy. We post rules on how our tools should be used, however, we cannot control the data processing practices of our users and we do not assume any responsibility for actions of our users who conduct surveys or of any other third parties. 

### Tell A Friend

If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about our Site, we will ask you for your friend's name and email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the Site. SurveyMonkey stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email and tracking the success of our referral program. 

Your friend may contact us at the relevant email address in the “Contact Us” section below to request that we remove this information from our database. 

### Co-branded Sites

From time to time we may partner with third parties to provide co-branded sites. In the event that you provide personally identifiable information on such a site, this privacy policy will continue to apply, unless that site has its own privacy policy. You retain full rights to you data and may either contact us at the relevant email address in the “Contact Us” section below to change or remove your data or alternatively you may ask us for a contact at the third party who can provide this service. 

### Opt-Out

In connection with promotions or other projects, we may ask you specifically whether you have objections against a certain kind of data use or sharing. If you opt-out under such circumstances, we will respect your decision. To opt-out of receiving further commercial emails, sharing of your information with our affiliates or to unsubscribe from services, please contact us at the relevant email address in the “Contact Us” section below. Please note that our affiliates and other data recipients have their own data privacy policies, which may differ from ours and you would have to contact them separately with respect to opt-out requests. 

### Access

If personal information you have submitted through the Site is no longer accurate, current, or complete, and you wish to update it, or you wish to delete it, please update your profile on the Site (e.g. [www.zoompanel.com](http://www.zoompanel.com/)) or send an email to the relevant email address in the “Contact Us” section below. We will amend any information that is not updateable on the Site upon your email request. We will respond to your request to access promptly, but in any event within 30 days. 

### Data Retention

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you with services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you with services, contact us at the relevant email address in the “Contact Us” section below. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, to resolve disputes, and to enforce our agreements. 

### Security

Transmissions over the Internet are never 100% secure or error-free. We do, however, take reasonable steps to protect your personal information from loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction. For example, we encrypt your registration information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). To learn more about SSL follow this link: <http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transport_Layer_Security>. It is your responsibility to safeguard any password and User ID you use to access the Site and to notify us if you ever suspect that your password or User ID has been compromised. You are solely responsible for any unauthorized use of the Site conducted via your password and User ID. 

### Children's Privacy

The Site is intended for adults. We do not intentionally or knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13 and we request that individuals under the age of 13 not submit any personal information on the Site. 

### Effective Date, Amendments

We reserve the right to change, modify, supplement or replace all or part of this privacy policy from time to time and in our sole discretion, but will alert you that changes have been made by indicating on the privacy policy the date it was last updated. Before any material changes to this privacy policy we will post a prominent notice on our Site before these changes go into effect. When you visit the Site, you are accepting the current version of this privacy policy as posted on the Site at that time. We recommend that users revisit this privacy policy on occasion to learn of any changes. 

### Contact Us

If you have a query or request specific to a product, you may contact us at the following email addresses: 

  * TrueSample: [support@truesample.com](mailto:support@truesample.com)
  * Zoomerang: [support@zoomerang.com](mailto:support@zoomerang.com)
  * ZoomPanel: [survey@zoompanel.com](mailto:support@zoompanel.com)

Please feel free to contact us with any comments, questions, complaints or suggestions you might have regarding the information practices described in this statement. You can contact us through this [privacy form](https://smforms.wufoo.com/forms/contact-surveymonkey-privacy/) or by mail to SurveyMonkey, 285 Hamilton Avenue, Suite 500, Palo Alto, CA 94301. If you do not receive acknowledgement of your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, you can also contact TRUSTe at <http://www.truste.org/consumers/watchdog_complaint.php>. TRUSTe will then serve as a liaison to resolve your concerns for any complaints arising from our TrueSample, Zoomerang and ZoomPanel websites.
